Preliminary Guide to the Department of Painting, School of Art and Architecture, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Painting, School of Art and Architecture, Yale University, records
1940-1958
RU 34
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
The records include lecture materials, notes, handouts, and assignments for courses in art history, composition, and painting taught by Richard A. Rathbone, professor of drawing and painting in the Yale Department of Painting.
Yale University. School of Art and Architecture
Rathbone, Richard Adams
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 18-E (YRG 18-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale Schools of Art and Architecture.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the School of Art, 1983.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by course title.
Scope and Contents
The records include lecture materials, notes, handouts, and assignments for courses in art history, composition, and painting taught by Richard A. Rathbone, professor of drawing and painting in the Yale Department of Painting.
Art history -- Study and teaching; Art schools; Art -- Study and teaching; Composition (Art) -- Study and teaching; Painting -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University. School of Art and Architecture
- Records, 1940-1958; Accession 1983-A-003
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  Lecture materials notes, handouts, assignments from courses in art history, composition and painting, taught by Richard A. Rathbone, (Y 1928) professor of drawing and painting. Also, notes from public lectures on art.
  - Art 10 Pictorial Art, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Art 16 Revised History of Ornament course, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art 17, 1947-1948, 1949-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Art 20, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Composition, Division I, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Composition, Division II, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Composition, 1947-1948, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Composition 20, 1950-1951, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Norfolk Art School Summer Course, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Painting 20, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Public lectures, 1948-1958 (Box 2, Folder 12 - 13)